Rockwell Kent papers 4079547
Rare Book and Manuscript Library
- Series III: Titled Drawings, Lithographs, Prints and Proofs
  - Island Inn, Monhegan Island, Maine; oversize pencil draft (Mapcase 13V-F-02)
  - Kayaker: See: Book illus.: Kent: Greenland journal
  - King Street; engraving, with poem (Box 5)
  - Land Legs; pen and ink drawing (Mapcase 13V-F-02)
  - Lobster fishermen at Monhegan; pencil & wash sketch (Box 7)
  - Lone man: See: Book illus.: Kent: Wilderness
  - The lookout: See: Book illus.: Kent: N by E (Random House)
  - The magpie's grave: See: Book illus.: Kent: Wilderness
  - [Male nude climbing a ladder] preliminary sketch, pencil, undated (Box 7)
  - Man: See: Book illus.: Kent: Wilderness
  - Man at mast:
    - 2 proofs (Box 7)
    - See also: Book illus.: Kent: N by E (Random House)
  - Masthead: See: Book illus.: Kent: N by E (Random House)
  - Max Bedacht; pencil drafts, 4p. (Box 7)
  - Meal time: See: Book illus.: Kent: Wilderness
  - Memory; pencil sketch (Box 7)
  - Militis in Galea nidum fecere columbae; oversize charcoal & ink sketch (Mapcase 13V-F-02)
  - Mt. Equinox; pencil drafts, 2p. (Box 7)
  - Mountain climber:
    - ink & pencil draft (Box 7)
    - pencil draft (Box 7)
  - New England; printed copy (Box 7)
  - Night: See: Book illus.: Kent: Wilderness
  - Night flight:
    - pencil draft (Box 7)
    - pencil sketch (Box 7)
  - Night watch: See: Book illus.: Kent: N by E (Random House)
  - Nightmare:
    - crayon & pencil sketch (Box 7)
    - lithograph (Box 7)
  - The North Wind: See: Book illus.: Kent: Wilderness
  - Northern night; pencil drafts, 2p. (Box 7)
  - Oak Street, New York, Lithograph., undated (Box 7)
  - Oarsman:
    - pencil draft (Box 7)
    - pencil sketch (Box 7)
  - The old ones; ink drafts & pencil drafts (Box 7)
  - On the height: See: Book illus.: Kent: Wilderness
  - Pasture gate; pencil draft (Box 7)
  - Pelagic reverie: See: Book illus.: Kent: Wilderness
  - Portrait of a child, or Portrait of Clara:
    - ink drafts, 2p. (Box 7)
    - printed copy (2) (Box 7)
  - Portrait of T.M. Cleland: See: Book illus.: Cleland, Thomas M.: The decorative work...
  - Precipice; photostat (Box 7)
  - Princeton tiger:
    - pencil draft (Box 7)
    - pencil sketch (Box 7)
  - Prison bars: See: Book illus.: Kent: Wilderness
  - Prometheus, or Prometheus unchained; oversize lithograph (Mapcase 13V-F-02)
  - Prometheus, or Prometheus unchained:
    - oversize pencil draft (Mapcase 13V-F-02)
    - photostats, 2p. & photostat mounted on folder (Box 7)
  - Rain torrents: See: Book illus.: Kent: Wilderness
  - "Reading Nick Carter," 1920. Signed H. Jr. Pen and ink on paper, 12 3/4 x 9 1/2 inches. (Larcada cat.no. 95 tentatively identifies this as a drawing for Rollo in Society, but it does not appear in the NY, G.P. Putnam's, ed.) (oversize), 1922 (Mapcase 13V-F-02)
  - Reaper: See: Advertising: Junior Art Patrons of America
  - Roof tree; pencil drafts (Box 7)
  - The ruins; ink sketch (Box 7)
  - Running water: See: Book illus.: Kent: Wilderness
  - St. Augustine; proof and printed copy (Box 7)
  - S[ally] K[ent] birthday picture (Box 7)
    - pencil draft (Box 7)
    - pencil sketch (Box 7)
  - Sea and sky; pencil draft (Box 7)
  - Seated nude; pencil draft (Box 7)
  - Self-portrait:
    - oversize charcoal sketch (Mapcase 13V-F-02)
    - see also: Jones, Dan Burne-bookplate (cataloged)
  - Self-portrait of artist bathing; ink sketch (Box 7)
  - [Self-portrait of the artist with a bird on his head] Lithograph, inscribed to Juliet, 1927 (Box 7)
  - [Koenig Smith] The sleeper: See: Book illus.: Kent: Wilderness
  - The Smith Act; pencil drafts, 2p. (Box 7)
  - The snow queen: See: Book illus.: Kent: Wilderness
  - Solar flare-up; oversize lithograph (2 copies) (Mapcase 13V-F-02)
  - Sophia: See: Book illus.: Kent: Greenland journal
  - The star-lighter: See: Book illus.: Kent: Wilderness
  - Starry night:
    - pencil draft (Box 7)
    - pencil sketch (Box 7)
  - Still the breath divine does move...; proof (Box 7)
  - Sunrise: See: Book illus.: Kent: Wilderness
  - Superman: See: Book illus.: Kent: Wilderness
  - Supplication; proof (Box 7)
  - Susanna, or The foot bath; pencil sketch (Box 7)
  - The temptation of Dr. Walter E. Traprock F.R.S.S.S.E.U. by Swank: See: Invitations: Dinner to Dr. Walter E. Traprock
  - This is my own; clipping (Box 7)
  - To Frances: See: Book illus.: Kent: N by E (Random House)-dedicatory leaf
  - To the stars; pencil draft (Box 7)
  - Unknown waters: See: Book illus.: Kent: Wilderness
  - Vermont winter: See: Book illus.: Kent: Rockwellkentiana-frontis.
  - Victory: See: Book illus.: Kent: Wilderness
  - View of Scandinavia: See: Book illus.: Beowulf
  - The vision: See: Book illus.: Kent: Wilderness
  - Voyager: See: Book illus.: Kent: N by E (Brewer & Warren)
  - Voyagers; pencil draft & printed copy (Box 7)
  - [Vulcan]:
    - pencil drafts, 6p. (Box 7)
    - oversize pencil drafts, 7p. (Box ?)
  - Vulcan, god of fire and of metal work; oversize printed copy (Mapcase 13V-F-02)
  - Waldo Pierce: See: Book illus.: Pierce, Waldo: Unser Kent
  - The wanderer; proofs, 2p. (Box 7)
  - The wayfarer; proof (Box 7)
  - Wayside Madonna:
    - oversize ink sketch (brown & gray) on proof (Mapcase 13V-F-02)
    - pencil draft (Box 7)
    - printed copy (green & brown on black) (Box 7)
    - proofs (black & White ) 2p. (Box 7)
    - oversize proofs (blue & black) 2p. (Mapcase 13V-F-02)
    - oversize proofs (blue & black on yellow) 2p. (Mapcase 13V-F-02)
  - The weather eye:
    - pencil draft (Box 7)
    - pencil sketches (Box 7)
    - oversize photostats of drawings, 2p. (Mapcase 13V-F-02)
  - Weltschmerz [1]: See: Book illus.: Kent: Wilderness
  - Weltschmerz [2]; pencil drafts (Box 7)
  - The whittler: See: Book illus.: Kent: Wilderness
  - Wilderness: See: Book illus.: Kent: Wilderness
  - "Wilderness" painting; pencil sketch (Box 7)
  - The windlass: See: Book illus.: Kent: Wilderness
  - Winter: See: Advertising: Provident Mutual Life Insurance Co. of Philadelphia
  - Woman: See: Book illus.: Kent: Wilderness
  - Workers of the world, unite!:
    - ink and pencil draft (Box 7)
    - pencil drafts, 2p. (Box 7)
  - Zarathustra and his playmates: See: Book illus.: Kent: Wilderness
  - Misc. proofs, 15p. & 3p. (Box 7)
  - __oversize 2p. (Mapcase 13V-F-02)
  - clipping (Box 7)
- Series IV: Advertising
  - Agfa (film)-trademark: pencil drafts (Box 8)
  - American Artists Group:
    - ink lettering (Box 8)
    - pencil drafts, 6p. (Box 8)
  - Ashlar Press: pencil draft, 1 page (Box 8)
  - Ashlar Press: pencil sketch, 1 page (Box 8)
  - American Car and Foundry Co.: Printed copy, 10. (Box 8)
  - American eagle:
  - pencil drafts, 3p. (Box 8)
  - American Export Lines:
    - ink draft, 1p. (Box 8)
    - ink sketches, 12p. (Box 8)
    - notes, 2p. (Box 8)
    - pencil drafts, 11p. (Box 8)
    - pencil sketches, 2p. (Box 8)
    - flag:
    - ink sketch (Box 8)
  - American Founders Corporation:
    - clipping (Box 8)
  - Armitage eagle: pencil drafts, 3 p. (Box 8)
  - Asgaard Farm:
    - ink sketch (Box 8)
    - pencil drafts, 3p. (Box 8)
    - pencil sketch (Box 8)
    - proof (Box 8)
    - brochure: mock-up copy (Box 8)
    - printed copy (2) (Box 8)
    - signcard: (Box 8)
    - oversize silkscreen print (Mapcase 13V-F-03)
    - "Celestial brew;" 2 printed labels (Box 8)
    - "Celestial brew;" 14 printed labels (Box 8)
    - "Rye flour;" printed label (Box 8)
    - "Wheat flour;" printed label (Box 8)
    - "Stone ground whole grain flour;" printed label (Box 8)
  - Asgaard records-"A Christmas Story":
    - ink and pencil drafts (Box 8)
    - pencil drafts, 4p. (Box 8)
  - Bittner & Galland (bookbinder):
    - pencil drafts, 2p. (Box 8)
    - pencil sketch (Box 8)
  - "Bonds to fit the investor":
    - pencil sketches, 8p. & clipping (Box 8)
  - Briarcombe Farm (Winona, MN):
    - printed copy (Box 8)
  - Cameron & Kahn, Inc. Publishers:
    - pencil drafts, 5p. (Box 8)
  - The Chicago Tribune:
    - oversize ink sketches, 4p. (Box 8)
    - pencil draft (Box 8)
  - Commercial National Bank and Trust:
    - oversize ink sketch (Mapcase 13V-F-03)
    - oversize pencil sketch (Mapcase 13V-F-03)
    - printed copy (Box 8)
  - Corporation Tar:
    - ink and pencil sketch (Box 8)
  - Curtiss Aeroplane & Motor Co.-"N.A.T.":
    - pencil drafts, 2p. (Box 8)
  - A.B. Dick Co.:
    - emblem:[Adam]: pencil draft (Box 8)
    - Egyptian]: pencil drafts, 2p. (Box 8)
    - "Electric pen;" printed copy (Box 8)
    - [Latin]: pencil draft (Box 8)
    - [Medieval]: pencil draft (Box 8)
    - [Moabitic]: pencil drafts, 2p. (Box 8)
    - [Prehistoric]: pencil draft (Box 8)
    - [Printing]: pencil draft (Box 8)
    - [Runic]: pencil draft (Box 8)
    - [Sinaitic]: pencil drafts, 2p. (Box 8)
  - Doubleday Book Shops:
    - Trademark; 5 printed bags (Box 8)
  - Duell, Sloan and Pearce, Inc.:
    - Trademark: pencil drafts, 3p. (Box 8)
  - English Book Shop:
    - pencil drafts, 3p. (Box 9)
  - General Electric:
    - calendar illus.: pencil draft (Box 9)
  - General Motors Radio:
    - printed copy (Box 9)
  - trademark: printed copy (Box 9)
  - Haig & Haig:
    - pencil drafts, 5p. (Box 9)
  - Halsey Stuard & Co.:
    - See: "Bonds to fit the investor"
  - The Harvard Society for Contemporary Art:
    - pencil drafts, 8p. (Box 9)
  - The Hideaway:
    - pencil drafts, 2p. (Box 9)
  - Hogarth mirrors:
    - proofs, 2p. (Box 9)
  - Japan Paper Company:
    - "Arnold Unbleached" [c1928]: printed leaflet (Box 9)
  - Junior Art patrons of America:
    - ink drafts (Box 9)
    - woodblock proofs, 2p. & clipping (Box 9)
  - The Lakeside Press (Chicago):
    - "Captain Ahab": oversize printed copy (Mapcase 13V-F-03)
    - "Close hauled;" oversize printed copy (Mapcase 13V-F-03)
    - label: pencil drafts, 2p. (Box 9)
    - "Rockwell Kent and his publishers" [1930] printed leaflet (Box 9)
    - trademark:pencil draft (Box 9)
  - Lentheric:
    - ink and pencil sketch (Box 9)
    - pencil drafts, 9p. (Box 9)
    - oversize pencil drafts, 2p. (Mapcase 13V-F-03)
    - Christmas card:
    - pencil drafts (Box 9)
    - proof (black and white for black plate) (Box 9)
    - proof (black and white for blue plate) (Box 9)
    - printed copy (Box 9)
    - lettering:
    - pencil draft (Box 9)
    - mailing label: (Box 9)
    - ink sketch (Box 9)
    - pencil drafts, 3p. (Box 9)
  - Life Magazine:
    - Christmas card, 1945. printed card and envelope (Box 9)
  - The Literary Guild of America, Inc.:
    - ink and pencil sketch (Box 9)
    - pencil drafts, 2p. (Box 9)
    - pencil sketches, 2p. (Box 9)
  - Marcus & Company (jewelers):
    - ink and pencil sketch (Box 9)
    - ink draft (Box 9)
    - ink sketch (Box 9)
    - pencil drafts, 19p. (Box 9)
    - printed page from Vanity Fair, & clipping, January 1928 (Box 9)
  - National Book Fair:
    - pencil sketch (Box 9)
  - National Society for the Prevention of Blindness:
    - printed copy (Box 9)
  - New Directions (Publishers):
    - trademark: pencil drafts, 2p. (Box 9)
  - New Hampshire Summer School of Art:
    - ink sketch and proof (Box 9)
  - P.O.N.:
    - oversize ink sketches, 4p. (Mapcase 13V-F-03)
    - pencil drafts, 7p. (Box 9)
    - oversize pencil drafts, 11p. (Mapcase 13V-F-03)
    - photostat (Box 9)
  - Provident Mutual Life Insurance Company of Philadelphia, PA:
    - blotter: printed copy (Box 9)
  - Quarto Club:
    - trademark: ink and pencil draft (Box 9)
  - Rahr Malting Company:
    - ink drafts (Box 9)
    - ink sketches, 2p. (Box 9)
    - pencil drafts, 11p. (Box 9)
  - Random House-Modern Library:
    - cover designs and devices: ink sketches, 2p. (Box 9)
    - pencil and ink drafts (Box 9)
    - trademark: pencil draft (Box 9)
  - Rapid Blue Print Co.: (Box 9)
    - "Joseph the Carpenter and his son;" pencil draft (Box 9)
  - Rockwell Kent ... architectural and general designing and rendering in any medium: printed copy (Box 9)
  - Schering Corporation:
    - pencil sketch (Box 10)
    - "Dysmenorhea;" pencil sketch (Box 10)
    - "Functional bleeding;" pencil draft (Box 10)
    - pencil sketch (Box 10)
    - oversize watercolor sketch (Box ?)
    - "Habitual abortion;" pencil sketch (Box 10)
    - "Male climacteric;" oversize ink and charcoal sketch (Box 10)
    - pencil draft (Box 10)
    - Male postatesia"(À): pencil sketch (Box 10)
    - "Menopause;" ink and wash sketch (Box 10)
    - "Sexual infantilism;" pencil sketch (Box 10)
    - "Sterility;" pencil sketch (Box 10)
  - Sears, Roebuck and Co.: (Box 10)
    - background materials: photostats, 22p. (Box 10)
    - copy: pencil draft (Box 10)
    - farmland: pencil drafts, 2p. (Box 10)
    - lettering: ink draft (Box 10)
    - pencil drafts, 2p. (Box 10)
    - soldier: pencil drafts, 2p. (Box 10)
    - Statue of Liberty: gray and black ink draft (Box 10)
    - pencil drafts, 5p. (Box 10)
  - Sharpe & Dohme Vitamins:
    - pencil drafts, 16p. (Box 10)
    - stencil (Box 10)
    - watercolor sketches, 8p. (Box 10)
    - oversize watercolor sketch (Mapcase 13V-F-03)
  - Sherman-Williams Paints:
    - clipping (Box 10)
  - "Ships":
    - oversize ink sketch (Mapcase 13V-F-03)
    - oversize pencil sketch (Mapcase 13V-F-03)
  - Steinway & Sons:
    - ink sketch (Box 10)
    - pencil drafts, 7p. (Box 10)
  - Steinway & Sons:
    - Ink sketch (Box 10)
    - Pencil drafts, 7p. (Box 10)
  - The Story Press:
    - trademarks: pencil drafts, 6p. (Box 10)
  - A Summer School of Art:
    - Monhegan Island Coast of Maine: proof (Box 10)
  - 20th Century Fox:
    - pencil draft (Box 10)
    - oversize pencil draft (Mapcase 13V-F-03)
  - United Airlines:
    - Christmas card: pencil drafts, 6p. (Box 10)
    - misc. printed, 3 items (Box 10)
  - U.S. Pipe & Foundry Co.:
    - pencil drafts, 5p. (Box 10)
    - oversize pencil sketches, 4p. (Box 10)
  - Veritas Caput Press:
    - trademark: oversize ink lettering (Box 10)
  - The Vermont Symphony Orchestra:
    - program: printed copy (Box 10)
    - program cover: mock-up (Box 10)
    - pencil drafts, 2p. (Box 10)
    - proofs, 7p. (Box 10)
  - Viking Press:
    - trademark: proof (Box 10)
  - WHW:
    - trademark: pencil drafts, 2p. (Box 10)
  - Westchester County Recreation Commission:
    - ink and pencil draft (Box 10)
    - pencil sketches, 3p. (Box 10)
  - Westinghouse Electric:
    - pencil draft (Box 10)
    - printed recipe booklet and clipping (Box 10)
  - Wilson Mechanical Instrument Co., Inc.:
    - See: Titled drawings, etc.: Vulcan ...
  - Weyerhaeuser Timber Co.:
    - pencil drafts, 3p. (Box 10)
    - Christmas card: pencil drafts, 2p. (Box 10)
  - Wiesenberger & Co. (Stockbrokers): (Box 10)
    - pencil drafts, 2p. (Box 10)
    - proofs, 2p. (Box 10)
  - Misc.-catering service: (Box 10)
    - pencil drafts and ink drafts, 3p. (Box 10)
    - proof & printed copy (Box 10)
  - Misc.:
    - ink and pencil drafts, 2p. (Box 10)
    - ink sketches, 4p. (Box 10)
    - pencil drafts, 26p. (Box 10)
    - oversize pencil draft (Mapcase 13V-F-03)
    - clippings, 4p. (Box 10)
- Series V: Architecture
  - Bungalow for Thomas C. Mackinson:
    - pencil & watercolor sketch & plan (Box 11)
    - oversize pencil technical drawing of section (Mapcase 13V-F-04)
  - Cellar window frames:
    - oversize pencil and watercolor drawing (Mapcase 13V-F-04)
  - [Churches]:
    - pencil sketches, 2p. (Box 11)
  - Churches in Venice:
    - oversize ink and watercolor renderings, 2p. (Box 11)
  - Colonial country houses ... New England: Griggs Downer House, Brookline, M.A.: Arnold House, New Haven, C.T.: oversize pencil and ink sketches __ (Box 11)
  - Colonial country houses ... Longfellow house, Cambridge, M.A.: King Hooper House, Danvers, M.A.: (Box 11)
    - oversize pencil and ink sketches (Mapcase 13V-F-04)
  - Colonial country houses ... the South: Hayward House, Charleston, S.C.: (Box 11)
    - oversize pencil and ink sketch (Mapcase 13V-F-04)
  - Colonial country houses ... White-hall, Severn, M.D.: Tulip Hill, West River, M.D.: (Box 11)
    - oversize pencil & ink sketches (Mapcase 13V-F-04)
  - Colonial country houses V. in New England and the South. Miles Brewton House, Charleston, S.C., 1760 "Tulip Hill," West River, M.D., 1750. 1903.: (Box 11)
    - Watercolor and pencil on paper, 24 x 17 in. (Larcarda cat.no. 98). (Box 11)
  - Colonial porch:
    - ink sketch (red, green, black) (Box 11)
  - Columnar arrangement:
    - oversize pencil and watercolor sketch (Mapcase 13V-F-04)
  - Coved ceilings in Italy: Pal. Farnese, Caprarola: (Box 11)
    - oversize ink sketch (Mapcase 13V-F-04)
  - Coved ceilings in Italy: Pontifical Palace, Vatican: (Box 11)
    - oversize ink sketch (Mapcase 13V-F-04)
  - Coved ceilings in Italy: Villa Madama, Rome Piccolomini Library, Sienna: (Box 11)
    - oversize ink sketch (Mapcase 13V-F-04)
  - [Design for a garden pavillion]:
    - oversize watercolor section (Mapcase 13V-F-04)
  - Design for a two-storey arcade:
    - oversize watercolor section (Mapcase 13V-F-04)
  - Fenestration of ... English Ren. Houses:
    - oversize pencil & crayon sketches, 2p. (Mapcase 13V-F-04)
  - Fenestration of ... German Ren. Houses: Architectural decoration confined to the gables: (Box 11)
    - oversize pencil and crayon sketches (Mapcase 13V-F-04)
  - Fenestration of ... German Ren. Houses: Buildings having pilasters or columns on the facade: (Box 11)
    - oversize pencil & crayon sketches (Mapcase 13V-F-04)
  - Fenestration of ... German Ren. Houses: Facades with pilasters or columns confined to the gables or entirely without them: (Box 11)
    - oversize pencil and watercolor sketches (Mapcase 13V-F-04)
  - Fenestration of ... German Ren. Houses: Facades without architectural decoration: (Box 11)
    - oversize pencil & crayon sketches (Mapcase 13V-F-04)
  - A garden entrance:
    - watercolor sketch (Box 11)
  - George Rogers Clark Memorial (Vincennes, Ind.), plan & cross-sections: (Box 11)
    - photostats, 7p. (Box 11)
  - Kent house: library mantle details:
    - oversize blueprint (Mapcase 13V-F-04)
    - pencil notes, 3p. (Box 11)
  - Palaces in Italy: Irregular plans:
    - oversize ink sketches, 2p. (Mapcase 13V-F-04)
  - Palaces in Italy: Rectangular plans:
    - oversize ink sketches (Mapcase 13V-F-04)
    - [plumbing]:
    - pencil sketch (Box 11)
  - [Rockwell Kent's living room (first house)]:
    - pencil sketches (Box 11)
  - [townhouse facade]:
    - oversize ink & wash sketch (Mapcase 13V-F-04)
  - 1262 Richmond Terrace, West New Brighton, Staten Island:
    - pencil sketch (Box 11)
    - ink and pencil sketches, 2p. (Box 11)
    - pencil notes (Box 11)
    - pencil sketches, 25p. (Box 11)
    - oversize pencil sketches, 2p. printed items, 7p.
- Series VI:Book Illustration
  - Aldington, Richard
    - All men are enemies. New York, Doubleday, Doran, 1933
      - book jacket: (Box 12)
      - pencil drafts (Box 12)
      - title-page: (Box 12)
      - pencil draft lettering: (Box 12)
      - pencil & ink draft (Box 12)
    - Very Heaven. New York, Doubleday, Doran, 1937
      - prospectus: (Box 12)
      - printed leaflet (Box 12)
  - Alexander, L.M.
    - Candy. New York, Dodd Mead, 1934
      - book jacket: (Box 12)
      - pencil drafts book jacket: (Box 12)
      - See: Bookplate: Lawrenceville School
      - "Coon:" ink sketch (Box 12)
      - "Georgia Beele:" ink sketch (Box 12)
      - proofs, 3p. (Box 12)
  - Allen, Harvey
    - Anthony Adverse. (not publishedÀ):
      - book jacket: (Box 12)
      - pencil drafts (Box 12)
  - American Institute of Graphic Arts.
    - Fifty prints exhibited by the Institute, 1927. New York, W.E. Rudge [c1928]:
      - frontspiece: See: Titled drawings, etc.: The Wanderer
  - Anderson, Hans Christian
    - The wild swans. (not published):
      - chapter heading, p.27: (Box 12)
      - ink sketch chapter heading, p.27: (Box 12)
      - pencil drafts, 4p. mock-up of text, p.27, 3p. (Box 12)
      - ink sketches, 3p. (Box 12)
      - pencil drafts, 4p. (Box 12)
  - Aymar, Gordon Christian
    - A treasury of sea stories. New York, A.S. Barnes [1948]
      - 10 illus. (2 sets) on 10 photostats (Box 12)
  - Beowulf. New York, Random House, 1932
    - book jacket: pencil drafts, 2p. (Box 12)
    - clippings, 2p. (Box 12)
    - cover design oversize pencil drafts and ink drafts, 3p. (Mapcase 13V-F-05)
    - facing p.8: ink lettering (Box 12)
    - facing p.8: oversize pencil drafts, 2p. (Mapcase 13V-F-05)
    - facing p.38: pencil drafts, 2p. (Box 12)
    - facing p.38: oversize pencil sketch (Mapcase 13V-F-05)
    - facing p.54: pencil draft (Box 12)
    - facing p.70: pencil draft (Box 12)
    - facing p.70: oversize pencil drafts, 2p. (Mapcase 13V-F-05)
    - facing p.112: pencil drafts, 2p. (Box 12)
    - facing p.112: oversize pencil drafts, 2p. (Mapcase 13V-F-05)
    - facing p.136: pencil draft (Box 12)
    - facing p.136: oversize pencil draft (Mapcase 13V-F-05)
    - illustration not used: oversize pencil draft (Mapcase 13V-F-05)
    - initial letters: ink and pencil drafts, 5p. (Box 12)
    - initial letters: ink sketches, 4p. (Box 12)
    - initial letters: pencil drafts, 5p. (Box 12)
    - initial letters: watercolor & pencil sketch (Box 12)
    - initial letters-lists, 3p. (Box 12)
    - lettering: oversize ink draft (Mapcase 13V-F-05)
    - lettering: ink drafts, 3p. (Box 12)
    - spine title lettering: pencil draft (Box 12)
    - title-page: ink and pencil draft (Box 12)
    - title-page: ink and pencil sketch (Box 12)
    - title-page illus.: pencil drafts, 2p. (Box 12)
    - title-page lettering: ink (Box 12)
    - title-page lettering: ink draft (Box 12)
    - title-page lettering: pencil draft (Box 12)
    - type: page proofs, 16p. (Box 12)
  - The black bull. N.p., 1942. (not publishedÀ):
    - pencil drafts, 2p. (Box 12)
    - oversize pencil drafts, 2p. (Mapcase 13V-F-05)
  - Boccaccio
    - The Decameron... Garden City, NY, Garden City Pub. Co., 1949 (Box 12)
      - box label: charcoal draft (Box 12)
      - box label: pencil drafts, 4p. (Box 12)
      - box label-spine: pencil draft (Box 12)
      - facing p.133: ink and wash sketch (Box 12)
      - facing p.165: pencil draft (Box 12)
      - facing p.453: ink sketch (Box 12)
      - facing p.453: pencil drafts, 4p. (Box 12)
      - facing p.516: ink and pencil draft (Box 12)
      - misc. pencil drafts, 2p. (Box 12)
      - misc. oversize pencil draft (Mapcase 13V-F-05)
      - misc. (Box 12)
  - Boni, Albert
    - Paper book. Vol.III, August 1929. (Not published)
      - cover design: pencil drafts, 2p. (Box 12)
  - Bridges, Harry
    - Untitled book (illus. not used)
      - ink sketches, 10p. (Box 12)
      - pencil drafts (Box 12)
  - Broch, Theodor
    - The mountains wait. St. Paul, Webb, 1942
      - book jacket: pencil draft (Box 12)
      - cover design: pencil drafts, 2p. (Box 12)
      - ink drafts, 3p. (Box 12)
      - page mock-up, 4 pieces (Box 12)
      - page of proof text, 1p. (Box 12)
      - pencil drafts (Box 12)
      - title-page illus.: pencil drafts, 5p. (Box 12)
      - vignettes, pp.131 & 200: pencil drafts (Box 12)
  - Buchan, John
    - Mountain meadow. Boston, Houghton Mifflin, 1941
      - book jacket: pencil drafts, 2p. (Box 12)
      - poster: oversize printed copy (Mapcase 13V-F-05)
  - Butler, Samuel
    - Erewhon. New York. Limited Editions Club, 1934
      - colophon illus.: pencil drafts, 2p. (Box 12)
      - facing p.48: pencil draft (Box 12)
      - facing p.122: pencil draft (Box 12)
      - facing p.192: pencil draft (Box 12)
      - linecut at head of chapter 27: pencil draft (Box 12)
      - linecut at head of chapter 28: pencil draft (Box 12)
      - unused linecut: pencil draft (Box 12)
  - Casanova de Seingalt, Giacomo
    - The memoirs...N.p. Aventuros, 1925
      - book spine: pencil sketch (Box 13)
      - prospectus: printed copy (Box 13)
    - The memoirs...New York, Boni [c1932]
      - book spine: pencil drafts (Box 13)